Guide to the Richard Finnie Collection ARS.0117
Archive of Recorded Sound
Richard Finnie Collection
1951-1980
ARS.0117
8 boxes: 315 open reel tapes (64 3-5" reels; 251 7" reels); 2 small boxes of slides
Archive of Recorded Sound
Open reel tapes recorded by Richard Finnie, including Bechtel Corporation film soundtrack material featuring traditional music and sound effects from Asia, the Middle East, and elsewhere, and broadcasts and live performances of classical music, jazz, folk, and other types of music.
Access
Open for research; material must be requested at least two business days in advance of intended use. Contact the Archive for assistance.
Source
The Richard Finnie Collection was donated to the Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound by Anne Ackerman Finnie in 1987.
Scope and Contents
The Richard Finnie Collection consists of a variety of open reel tape recordings made by documentary filmmaker, photographer, ethnographer and historian Richard Sterling Finnie (1906-1987), largely in the 1950s and 60s. Finnie worked for the international engineering company Bechtel Corporation for twenty-five years, and as a producer for their industrial film division he recorded music from around the world, as well as sounds related to Bechtel's oil pipeline and refinery projects. This material was used in soundtracks for Bechtel films such as Oil Across Sumatra, Petrole de Zarzaitine, Exploring Libya, and Bechtel in Europe.
Finnie, who had extensive prior experience documenting his travels in Northern Canada, made on-location recordings of traditional music from such countries as Korea, Libya, Tunisia, Sumatra, South Africa, Lebanon, Cambodia and Venezuela, utilizing the talents of local musicians and songwriters. Rights contracts are enclosed with a few tapes; in fact Libyan composer Mohammed Murshan was hired to write a special Petroleum Song for Bechtel. Additionally, environmental sounds, such as street noise, a call to prayer, "mule cart sounds," "crowd noises at Tripoli race track," and an "overloaded radio," were recorded for sound effects and beds. Some of these field tapes also include Bechtel business matters (i.e. meetings, phone calls, and speech rehearsals).
In addition to his work with Bechtel (which ended with his retirement in 1968), Finnie captured copious amounts of radio broadcasts on tape, particularly from Pacifica station KPFA, but also from programs on KDFC, KCBS, KEAR, and KKHI. These include Phil Elwood's jazz shows, New York Philharmonic and San Francisco Symphony performances, rebroadcasts from classical music festivals such as Salzburg, Warsaw, Carmel Bach, Edinburgh, and Vienna, and a multitude of other programs. Finnie's radio tapes are a testament to the richness of Northern California radio offered during that time.
Finnie, who lived in Belvedere, California, was also a jazz fan, and the collection contains some remarkable artifacts, such as original Earl Hines and Muggsy Spanier Club Hangover recordings (recorded off-air with Robert L. Ingram), informal jam sessions with local traditional jazz musicians, Turk Murphy at Grace Cathedral (from a KMPX broadcast hosted by Phil Elwood), the Preservation Hall Jazz Band at Marin Junior College in 1975, and the audio portion of a Coleman Hawkins memorial television program from 1969.
The vast majority of recordings were made by Finnie himself, although there is not always attribution present. There are a few copies of commercially-released recordings, some of which were shellac discs borrowed from the Indonesian consulate. Most tapes contain inserted material such as notes, photographs, newspaper clippings, review logs, Bechtel contracts, and correspondence.
Arrangement
Tapes have been organized in the following general series: 1. Bechtel-related recordings (non-ethnic); 2. classical music broadcasts; 3. ethnic/field recordings and broadcasts (many of which were for Bechtel); 4. jazz recordings and broadcasts; 5. miscellaneous. Please note that many tapes contain multiple recordings and are grouped alphabetically according to the first words of the first recording listed on the tape box. Some tapes are edited transfers of other tapes in the collection, and may be listed elsewhere.
Related Materials
The Archive of Recorded Sound separately houses approximately sixty instantaneous discs recorded by Finnie, some of which are the original sources for tapes in this collection. Stanford University Special Collections holds the Richard Sterling Finnie Papers, 1945-1967 (M0694), which is focused primarily on Bechtel and also contains a variety of audiovisual media. The National Archives of Canada holds the Richard Sterling Finnie Fonds, 1890-1987.
Indexing Terms
Finnie, Richard Sterling; Bechtel Corporation.
- 1. Bechtel recordings (non-ethnic), etc.
  - S.D. Bechtel's Tribute to W. Morrison, 1965-08-02; 1 3" open reel tape (Audio 8)
  - Neil Buckley, piano. Lake Tahoe 7/13/63; Gordon Way Interview 9-10/62; Chocolate Bayou Dedication 12/4/1962, 1962-1963; 1 3" open reel tape (Audio 8)
  - Cal-Tex Voice Auditions, 1960-10-07; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
  - Chocolate Bayou Dedication Speeches, 1962-12-04; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
  - B.F. Fairless. Cuidad Bolivar 2/27/53; Fairless Works 6/20/54, 1953-1954; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
  - Fritz Speech Rehearsal; Alyce Story; South Seas Music on Dinah Shore Show; Lonnie Adair Ballads; Sidney Bechet Recordings; Sound Effects; Sfax Orchestra, 1960; 1 3" open reel tape (Audio 8)
  - Geneva. Al Moritz and Colleagues, 1963-11-01; 1 3" open reel tape (Audio 8)
  - Johanson Family 11/18/59 Concluded; N.Y. Management Meeting. Original Field Tape, 1959-11; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
  - C.B. Lester Interview for Bechtel Briefs Article 8/62; Mediterranean Pipeline Crossing Discussion; Bells of Strasbourg Cathedral; Purchasing, Pipeline Offices, Paris; Israel Leviant's Views on Story Treatment for Film and Book on Bechtel in Europe. Field tape, 1962; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
  - Luncheon at Mercier; Alexander Rignault Audition; Zelten Road, 1961; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
  - E.B. Mulkins, 1965-01; 1 3" open reel tape (Audio 8)
  - Music Box in London; Fragment of Phone Conversation; London Traffic Noise; Drafting Room Background; Purchasing Office with Typewriters; Walt Hillman At Radio, Ras Es Sider 5/9/62; Welding At Pipeline at Dahra; Radio Operator at Dahra; Libyan Voices and Effects, 1962-05; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
  - Rhine Crossing; Pipe-laying near Cologne; Supervisors Meeting, The Hague; London Office Meeting; A Visit to the Johansons, Copenhagen. Original Field Tape, 1959-11; 1 3" open reel tape (Audio 8)
  - Southern Pacific. Sound Effects (Bechtel) Reels 3, 5, 6, 3 5" open reel tapes (Audio 8)
  - Submarine Sounds; Ivan Manning And Clay Wheeler In Four-Handed Jam Session At Hawaiian, 1960-08-03; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
  - Slides: Zelten, Libya; Kuwait [oil refinery?] 11-12/58, 1958; 2 boxes (Box 8)
- 2. classical music broadcasts
  - festival broadcasts, 1958-1963
    - Aldeburgh Festival, KPFA. Menuhin, Britten, 1959; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - Ascona Festival; Bergen Festival, 1962; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - Ascona Festival; Golden Voices - Caruso, 1962; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - Carmel Bach Festival, KPFA, 1960-07-23; 2 7" open reel tapes (Audio 7)
    - Carmel Bach Festival, KPFA, 1961-07; 2 7" open reel tapes (Audio 6, Audio 7)
    - Festival Casals; David Del Tredici live KPFA 3/30/59, 1958-1959; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - Casals Festival, KPFA, 1959; 3 7" open reel tapes (Audio 4)
    - Chimay Festival '60 KDFC International Music Hall 12/24/61; Presti and Lagoya, KPFA from CDC 9/1/63, 1960-1963; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - Chimay Festival; Liege Festival, 1962; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - Chimay Festival, Zabaleta KPFA, 1963-08; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - Donaueschingen Festival '58 KPFA, 1960; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - Dubrovnik Festival; Golden Voices - Kathleen Ferrier. KPFA, 1960; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - Edinburgh Festival KPFA, 1958; 2 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - Edinburgh Festival '63; Bergen Festival '63, 1963; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - Enesco Festival, Bucharest, Rumania. Menuhin- Brahms, Beethoven, 1959-04-10; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - Ghent Festival '62; A Concert From Berlin, 1963; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - A Concert from Liege, 1961-09-15; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - Liege Festival, 1962; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - Haslemere FestivaL, KPFA, 1959; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - Montreux Festival, KPFA. Ravel, Debussy, 1961; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - Les Nuits de Sceaux; Delius; KPFA Studio Concert. William Corbett Jones, piano, 1959-01; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - Les Nuits de Sceaux, KPFA, 1958; 2 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - Les Nuits de Sceaux, KPFA, 1959-01-18; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - Prades Festival, KPFA, 1959; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - Prades Festival; Salzburg Festival, 1959; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - Prague Spring Festival, 1962-10-25; 3 7" open reel tapes (Audio 1, Audio 2)
    - Salzburg Festival broadcasts
      - Salzburg Festival, 1957; 8 7" open reel tapes (Audio 1, Audio 7)
      - Salzburg, KEAR, KPFA, 1958; 10 7" open reel tapes (Audio 2, Audio 7)
      - Salzburg Festival, KPFA, 1959; 9 7" open reel tapes (Audio 1, Audio 2, Audio 6)
      - Salzburg Festival, 1961; 4 7" open reel tapes (Audio 2)
      - Salzburg Festival, 1962-12-09; 17 7" open reel tapes (Audio 1, Audio 2, Audio 3)
    - Sibelius Festival broadcasts
      - Sibelius Festival, KPFA, 1959; 2 7" open reel tapes (Audio 3)
      - Sibelius Festival, KPFA, 1960; 3 7" open reel tapes (Audio 2)
      - Sibelius Festival; Chimay Festival, 1963-08; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
      - Sibelius Festival '63, 1963; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - From Spoleto, KPFA. Bach, Brahms, 1962; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - Vienna Festival broadcasts
      - Vienna Festival, KPFA, KCBS, 1961; 13 7" open reel tapes (Audio 1, Audio 2, Audio 7)
      - Vienna Festival, KPFA, KDFC, 1962; 8 7" open reel tapes (Audio 1, Audio 7)
      - Vienna Festival 1962. Bruckner's Ninth, Te Deum; Grieg Festival 1962. KDFC, 1963; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - Warsaw Festival; Edinburgh Festival. KPFA, 1959; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - Warsaw Festival, KPFA, 1959; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
  - New York Philharmonic broadcasts, 1956-1966
    - Mitropoulos, NY Philharmonic. CBS. Strauss, Stara, 1956-10-28; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - Bernstein, NY Philharmonic, CBS. Beethoven, Mozart, Stravinsky, Ravel, 1956-12-16; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - NY Philharmonic, Menuhin. KCBS 12/15/57; Bernstein, NY Philharmonic 8/28/58, 1957-1958; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - Mitropoulos, NY Philharmonic. KCBS 11/3/57. Prokofiev; Eva Heinitz Recital, KPFA 3/3/64, 1957-1964; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - Bernstein, NY Philharmonic, CBS. Haydn, Bartok, Ravel, 1957-01-06; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - NY Philharmonic, CBS. Prokofiev, Sibelius, 1957-01-20; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - NY Philharmonic, CBS. Bach, Schuller, Beethoven, Glazinov, 1957-03; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - NY Philharmonic on CBS, 1957-03-03; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - NY Philharmonic, CBS. Mussorgsky, Grieg, 1957-03-31; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - NY Philharmonic, CBS. Lalo, Brahms, Wagner, 1957-04-07; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - Shippers, NY Philharmonic, KCBS 10/27/57; Mitropoulos, NY Philharmonic. Prokofiev 10/13/57, 1957-10; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - Mitropoulos, NY Philharmonic. KCBS, 1957-11; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - NY Philharmonic, KCBS, 1958-03-16; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - Bernstein, NY Philharmonic, KCBS. Vivaldi, Copland, 1958-12-07; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - Bernstein, NY Philharmonic, KCBS. Milhaud, Gershwin, 1958-12-14; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - Bernstein, NY Philharmonic KCBS 2/1/59; Monteux, NY Philharmonic KCBS 3/1/59, 1959; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - Bernstein, NY Philharmonic, KCBS 2/59; KPFA live studio concert 3/30/59 David Del Tredici, pianist. La Monte Young, Seymour Shifrin. Alla Von Buch, pianist. Shostakovich, Scriabin, Beethoven, 1959; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - Bernstein, NY Philharmonic. Piston, Ravel, Walton, 1959-02-15; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - Monteux, NY Philharmonic. Ravel, Berloiz, 1959-03; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - Bernstein, NY Philharmonic, KCBS. Mahler, Hindemith, 1960-02; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - Bernstein, NY Philharmonic, KCBS. Mahler, 1960-02-21; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - Walter, NY Philharmonic. Mahler, Das Lied. KCBS, 1960-04-17; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - Shapira, NY Philharmonic KKHI 3/14/65; Nelsova and Newmark, Hindemith KPFA 9/19/63; BBC Symphony, Mahler 9/21/63, 1963-1965; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - Krips, NY Philharmonic, KKHI 2/21/65; Paray, San Francisco Symphony KKHI 2/26/65, 1965-02; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - Bernstein, NY Philharmonic. Smit, Copland. KKHI, 1966-02-12; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
  - San Francisco Symphony broadcasts, 1964-1980
    - Krips, San Francisco Symphony. KKHI. Mozart, Brahms, Mahler, 1964-02-07; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - Krips, San Francisco Symphony. Mozart. KKHI, 1965-03-19; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - Krips, San Francisco Symphony, 1970-03-05; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - San Francisco Symphony Orchestra, KKHI, 1972-02-18; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - De Waart, San Francisco Symphony. KQED, 1980-08-24; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - miscellaneous classical broadcasts
    - BBC Symphony Orchestra, KPFA, 1960; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - BBC Mahler 6th Conclusion 9/21/63; Donaueschingen, Stravinsky 12/7/63; Mozart Recital, Daniel Abrams 2/9/64, 1963-1964; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - Beecham, Royal Philharmonic, Berlioz. KPFA, 1963; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - Belgium, Segovia KPFA, 1961-07; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - Boston Symphony, KBRG. Gunther Schuller, Seven Studies; Van Cliburn-Liszt, 1965-01-27; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - Capella Strings live studio recital, KPFA, 1958-12; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - Van Cliburn in Moscow, 1958-12-28; 2 7" open reel tapes (Audio 1)
    - Kathleen Ferrier BBC; Sounds Our Fathers Heard. KPFA, 1960-03-19; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - The Hague Philharmonic, KPFA, 1964; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - Handel, Royal Fireworks Music; U.C. May Festival, Milhaud. KPFA, 1959-05-29; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - Handel-Purcell Anniversary, BBC program. KPFA, 1959; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - International Music Hall, KDFC 12/3/61 Martine, Corelli, Bartok; Vienna Festival '61 KPFA, 1961; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - International Music Hall, KDFC. Strauss, Leclair, Ingegneri, Haydn, 1961-12-10; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - Library of Congress Concerts, KPFA, 1961; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - Ludwig, London Symphony. Mahler, KPFA, 1960; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - Music From the Netherlands, KPFA, 1961; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - Music From the Netherlands, KPFA, KDFC. Handel, Mozart, Roussel, 1962; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - Music From the Netherlands, KPFA, 1962-01-20; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - Netherlands Chamber Orchestra; Library of Congress Concert, Budapest Quartet. KPFA, 1961; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - Netherlands Symphony; Quarteto Italiano, Library of Congress. KPFA, 1961-06; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - Ormandy, Philadelphia Orchestra. KDFC 3/1/64; Eva Heinitz Studio Recital KPFA 3/3/64, 1964; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - Quarteto Italiano, Utrecht Orchestra, KPFA, 1961-06; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - Sibelius, Labrador Score. Finnie Arrangement, 1967; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - Sons of Bach. East German Radio. KPFA, 1962-01-27; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - Standard Oil of California Symphony, W.A. Palmer experimental stereo recording, 1954; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - TWA Royal Composers, KKHI, 1964-01-14; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - Tanya Ury Plays An Ancient Pleyel, KPFA, 1963-07-16; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - Verdi's Requiem from Vienna, KPFA, 1963-12-13; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
- 3. ethnic/field recordings and broadcasts
  - American folk, 1952-1960
    Scope and Contents
    Like Richard Finnie, Prentice G. "Spike" Downes (1909-1959) was an explorer and ethnographer in Canada's far north, known for his work with Cree and Dene people as well as his mapping expeditions. These tapes suggest that he was also an amateur musician, and although the type of material performed is unknown, the songs appear to be related to the occupational folk songs of pipeline workers. Likewise, Lonnie Adair's choice of songs are not evident without listening (probably William Olonzo "Lonnie" Adair, 1910-2007).
    - Lonnie Adair, voice and guitar [photograph affixed to tape box], 1960-04-12; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - Spike Downes in Concord, Mass., Pipeliners Mobile Radio Talk [correspondence between Finnie and Mrs. Downes enclosed], 1952; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
      Downes, P. G. (Prentice Gilbert), 1909-
    - P.G. "Spike" Downes. Words and Music. Recorded by RF, 1952-06-24; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
  - Australian Folk Songs. Lionel Long, 1965; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
  - Brazil, Mato Grosso (Weyer), 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
  - Cambodia
    - Cambodian Royal Palace Orchestra - Filtered Transfer, 1958-10-16; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - Royal Cambodian Ballet, Palace Hotel. AC Hum, Transfer from Original, 1958-10-16; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 7)
  - Image of Chile, KPFA, 1964; 2 7" open reel tapes (Audio 4)
  - Chinese Classical Pipa Music, KPFA, 1963-05-14; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  - Cuba and Trinidad [from discs], 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
  - Bechtel in Europe. Music and Effects, 1964-03-23; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  - Hawaiian Orchestra at Royal Hawaiian 8/60; Equipment Sounds for Submarine Pipeline Operation; Marty and Ted Elliot Duet 9/60, 1960; 1 3" open reel tape (Audio 8)
  - Indian Music: Talas, Ragas. Ethnic Music, KPFA, 1962-12-08; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
  - Indonesia/Bali/Sumatra, 1953-1958
    - Music of Bali, courtesy Indonesian Consulate, 1958; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - Music of Bali; Indonesia, Popular. Radio Republik Indonesia. Transfer From Tape Loaned By Indonesian Consulate, San Francisco, 1958-10-14; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - Indonesian Popular Music from 78 rpm Discs; Rumbai Five, Neles Sahamaja, Leader and Singer. From Finnie Original 8/2/58, 1957-1958; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - Folk Music of Indonesia. 1.Transferred from tape borrowed from Indonesian Consulate; 2. Radio Republik Indonesia Transcription Service 78 rpm Disc Transfers, 1953; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - Sumatra, 1958-02; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - Oil Across Sumatra. Live Sound, 1957-1958; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - Selematan Speeches at Dumai, Sumatra. Caltex Pacific Oil Company, 1958-07-15; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - Sumatra. Classroom; Pipe-making, 1957; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - Sumatra, Sounds. Test Recordings: Mostly Chinese Music From Radio; P.L. Shore Dictating on Promotion of Private Enterprise in Indonesia; Pipeline Spread; Pumping Well; Jungle Sounds; Hornbill; Indonesian Story; Jungle Clearing; Chinese Story, 1958; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - Sumatra. Sounds and Music, 1957; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - Rumbai Recital, Sumatra. Original and Transfers, 1958-02-13; 5 5" open reel tapes (Audio 8)
  - Christmas in Italy, KPFA, 1962; 2 open reel tape :1 5" reel; 1 7" reel (Audio 3, Audio 8)
  - Japan
    - Gagaku; Japanese Music. KPFA, 1962-03; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - A Concert of Japanese Music, KPFA, 1965-02-12; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  - Korea
    - Groundbreaking at Tangin-Ri, Korea. Soundtrack Transfer from 35MM Korean Newsreel Footage, 1955; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - Korea, 1956; 3 5" open reel tapes (Audio 8)
    - Korean folk songs - PBC waitresses in Masan 4/21/56; A Night at Nick's [nightclub recording], 1956; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - Court Music Recital, Seoul, Korea. Korean Court Orchestra (Lee Palace), 1956-04-26; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - Korea - Chin Mae, etc., 1956-04; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - Music of Korea and Tahiti. Lee Palace Orchestra and Folk Singers, Recorded in South Korea by RF (Transferred Selections); Lure of Tahiti, ABC Paramount [photo and program from Korean performance enclosed], 1956-04; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - Korean Music. A Recital by Hwang Byongki, KPFA, 1965-08-07; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
  - Middle East/North Africa
    - Music of Aden and Lebanon 5/19/1957; Music of Lebanon 11/14/1951. Finnie Recordings, 1951-1957; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - Music of Aden. Aden Musical Association [photographs enclosed and affixed to tape box], 1957-05-19; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - Oil from Zarzaitine [Algeria]. Music and Effects, 1961-04-17; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - Oil from Zarzaitine. North African Music. pt.1, 1961-04-17; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - Oil from Zarzaitine effects, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - Bahrain. Music and Sounds. Recorded by Bapco, 1957-06; 2 5" open reel tapes (Audio 8)
    - Kuwait Orchestra. Original and Transfers, 1957-06-11; 4 open reel tapes: 2 5" reels; 2 7" reels (Audio 8)
    - Music of Lebanon. Original, 1951-11; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - Exploring Libya. Sound Effects and Voices Recorded on Location, 1960-05; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - Exploring Libya. Petroleum Song; Call to Prayer [lyrics to Libyan Petroleum Song by Mohammed Murshan enclosed], 1960-09; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - Exploring Libya. Music Composed by Mohhamed Murshan of Libyan Broadcasting Station. Recorded in Tripoli 1960. Equalized transfer, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - [Libya] Petroleum Song by Mohammed Murshan, Master, 1960; 1 3" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - Music of Libya, Murshan. Master, 1960; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - Music of Libya. Composed by Mohammed Murshan. Played by Libyan Broadcasting Station Orchestra, 1964-07; 2 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - Music of Libya. Aoud, Nye, 1965-02-17; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - Libya. Sirtica Music. Murshan, 6 3" open reel tapes (Audio 5)
    - Music of Tunisia. Sfax Orchestra 11/26/60; Ivan Manning and Clay Wheeler, 4 hand piano at Royal Hawaiian, Honolulu 8/3/60; Bill Dunham piano, Tripoli 12/8/60, 1960; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - Music of Libya, Transfer. Murshan; Call to Prayer, 1960-05; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - Moslem Call to Prayer, Tripoli, Libya, 1960-05-31; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - Tuareg Music from Ghadames. From Master Recording by Issa Belkheir, Tripoli, Libya, 1960-12; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - North Africa Field Tape. Miscellaneous Live Sound for Exploring Libya; Sfax Orchestra; Bill Dunham Piano; Zelten Field Drilling; Marsa al Brega, 1960; 1 3" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - Field Recording in Saudi Arabia 5-6/57, 1957; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - Music of Hasa, Saudi Arabia. Sa'ad Bin Majid, Nye With Essa Bakeet, Percussion. Finnie Recording, 1957-05-26; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - Tunisian Music, Original. Off-the-Air Through Mike. Courtesy Herb Coste, Sfax, 1960; 1 3" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - Musique Tunisienne. Original. Orchestre Aloulou. Hotel des Oliviers. Sfax, Tunisia, 1960-11-26; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)